linkedin.com/in/nealtaylor98 github.com/nealtaylor98

B.IT

Passionate Software Developer and Open Source contributor with 6 years of experience working with technology. Driven by delivering immaculate software to the wider world using .NET React and Cloud technologies with a focus on user-friendly development, testing, and experience handling large databases holding secure customer data.

Work Experience

Software Developer

Interfi Systems Pty Ltd

Jan 2024-Present

Feature team

Geelong, Victoria

- Heavily involved in the conversion of 50+ Api controllers to newer .Net Core project
- Key contributor in recreating Desktop application using React, Tanstack Query, Material UI
- Developed logic intensive features such as allowing users to partially discharge securities from a loan
- Discovered issues and proposed solutions to code around compounding interest. Potentially saving users hundreds of dollars annually
- Maintained and developed legacy software using .NET Framework, WinForms, .Net Framework, JQuery and other technologies.
- Owned close to 30% of the tickets working in a team of 5
- Developed secure processing of payment tasks with Payment Providers and file parsing from banks.
- Successfully upgraded key packages (e.g. react-router-dom v4 to v6)

IT Support Engineer BJS Insurance Group

Operations Team

Melbourne, Victoria

- Migrated end users to Azure Domain
- Task automation using Powershell such as user onboardings/offboardings
- Backup monitoring and maintenance
- End-User support
- Asset tracking

IT Project Management Trainee

Moorabool Shire Council

2021-2022

2023-2024

Baccus Marsh, Vic

- Oversaw projects and ensured that vendors/contractors met deadlines
- Organised user-acceptance testing for major replacement of CRMS

Information Services Team

Corangamite Shire Council

2017-2020

Camperdown, Victoria

- Evaluated, discussed and implemented replacement of company-wide anti-virus software
- Set up and configured remote applications server to allow end-users to access company applications without the need of terminal servers
- Configuring business automations (Quick-add profiles) through company's Records Management System (Technology One ECM)
- Training end-users and new hires on how to use software

Education

• Bachelors' Information Technology - RMIT University

2022-2023

Completed in 2 years while working full time

Technologies and Languages

Languages: C#, Typescript/Javascript, Rust, Python, C/C++, Dart, SQL

• Technologies: Flask, Flutter, React, Tanstack, Material UI, Git, Postman, GraphQL

• Other: Data structures and algorithms, Domain administration, DNS, AWS, Google Cloud Platform

Projects

• Bevy Game Engine: Contributor - Recent endeavour. Implementing bug fixes, documentation and reviewing PRs

Certifications

- Agile Ways of Working
- Creative Thinking
- Presenting using Story Telling